volvocars.com 2001-06-02

# Volvo Privacy Statement

VOLVO PRIVACY STATEMENT \- VOLVO DIVERSITY POLICY

**Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. & Volvo Finance North America, Inc. Privacy Policy and Securing Data**

This privacy policy and guideline is specific to Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. and Volvo Finance North America, Inc. located in the United States.

At Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. ("VCNA"), and Volvo Finance North America, Inc. ("VFNA"), we believe strongly in personal privacy for individuals and their families. Honesty and respect for personal security are highly valued at VCNA/VFNA and are issues we take as seriously as our continuing efforts in automotive safety. With the advent of the Internet, we can now collect customer information online, as well as through traditional channels, such as the telephone or customer surveys. Most Internet users welcome the fact that customized, relevant and timely information can be provided via the Internet.

VCNA and VFNA recognize that the growth of online services has created additional privacy concerns. It is for that reason that Volvo maintains a strict privacy policy to safeguard customer identifiable information and communications from unauthorized intrusions.

Privacy concerns focus on the protection of "customer identifiable" information which an individual reasonably expects to be kept private. As the term suggests, "customer identifiable" information is information which can be associated with a specific individual or entity, including, for example, a customer's name, address, or telephone number, e-mail address, and information about activities (online or otherwise) that are directly linked to them.

It is common practice and often a necessity for companies, governments, or other organizations to collect customer identifiable information in order to conduct business and offer services. For example, an internet referral service that refers car shoppers to local authorized retailers may collect customer identifiable information, such as name, address, telephone number, and a variety of other information, in the course of providing this service to a customer.

**I. Notice:**

The information which you supply VCNA/VFNA with or which VCNA/VFNA collects about you ("Information") may be used freely by VCNA/VFNA and other businesses owned by or affiliated with VCNA/VFNA's parent company, Ford Motor Company. We may also share Information with other persons to conduct our business, such as credit agencies, marketing and ad agencies, recordkeepers, service providers, and government entities. We may use Information in a variety of ways relating to our business, including developing services and marketing programs, analyzing customer preferences, and investigating and approving your credit.

**VCNA/VFNA Online Privacy Policy**  
How we collect and process the data you provide.

VCNA/VFNA has put in place the following Online Privacy Policy to protect customer identifiable information. This policy covers VCNA/VFNA and its subsidiaries, and applies to all customer identifiable information that VCNA/VFNA obtains when a customer registers for or uses a VCNA/VFNA online service, including visiting a VCNA/VFNA owned and controlled website ("Volvo Web Site"). VCNA/VFNA will continue to protect customer information derived from its sales of automobiles and related products and services in a manner consistent with federal regulations.

**VCNA/VFNA collect and use your information for specific purposes**  
VCNA/VFNA will collect and use customer identifiable information to create and inform you of products and services that better meet your needs, for billing purposes, or to anticipate and/or resolve problems with your service. This means that VCNA/VFNA may use your customer identifiable information to market new services to you that we think will be of interest to you, but we will not disclose your customer identifiable information to third parties that want to market products to you. When VCNA/VFNA uses other agents, contractors or companies to perform services on its behalf, VCNA/VFNA will use reasonable commercial efforts to ensure that the company protects your customer identifiable information in a manner consistent with this Policy.

To receive credit or other services from us, you may be required to provide personal information to VCNA or VFNA and/or an authorized Volvo Retailer which you select. When you utilize online credit application, you are submitting the information from your application to VFNA and an authroized Volvo Retailer which you specify. We may not be able to provide you with services through the Internet if you refuse to provide information to VFNA or your authorized Volvo Retailer. If you choose to provide us with information (whether actively or passively) by using our website, you acknowledge and agree you are doing so on a voluntary basis. You may see any authorized Volvo Retailer in person if you have any reservations about conducting business over the Internet.

**II Choice:**

**Opting out of Volvo marketing information**  
An individual may choose not to receive direct marketing communications from either VCNA or VFNA in connection with online services. Upon such choice, VCNA or VFNA (a) will not contact that individual directly with marketing messages about Volvo online services, and (b) will not use customer identifiable information obtained from that individual's registration for or use of an online service to contact that customer with marketing messages about any VCNA or VFNA products or services. An individual may communicate his or her choice not to receive such messages by e-mail and mail.

To inform VCNA that you do or do not wish to receive communications of certain kinds from VCNA, please do one of the following:

drop us a line - address the letter to:

Volvo Customer Service  
Attn: Privacy  
7 Volvo Drive  
Rockleigh, NJ 07647; or

send us an email at [customerservice@volvocars.com](mailto:customerservice@volvocars.com), with "Privacy" as the subject.

Customer-identifiable information which a visitor volunteers at any VCNA/VFNA Web Sites to inquire about or order Volvo products or services will be protected just as if the information had been provided under more traditional ways of ordering that product or service.

Back to Top

**III Access:**

**Customer Concerns**  
If you are a consumer with concerns about the Volvo online privacy policy or its implementation you may contact us via email at customerservice@volvocars.com, with "Privacy" in the subject line.

**Changes in Practices**  
Volvo will keep its Privacy Policy current, and make best efforts to promptly update this web page every time there is a change to this policy.

**IV Security:**

Volvo has implemented technology and security features and strict policy guidelines to safeguard the privacy of your customer identifiable information from unauthorized access or improper use, and we will continue to enhance our security procedures as new technology becomes available. At VCNA and VFNA, information which you transmit to us on the Internet is secure and/or encrypted or protected by VCNA/VFNA. Once we receive it, Information is stored securely within VCNA and/or VFNA.

**E-mail Contents**  
Volvo will not read or disclose to third parties private e-mail communications that are transmitted using Volvo services except as required to operate the service or as otherwise authorized by law.

**Improper Conduct**  
Volvo may also use customer identifiable information to investigate and help prevent potentially unlawful activity, or activity that threatens the company or otherwise violates the customer agreement for any products or services that Volvo provides.

**Additional Privacy Protections for Children Using the Internet**  
Volvo joins the industry in recognizing that children, including young teens, may not be able to make informed choices about personal information requested online. Accordingly, Volvo does not knowingly target children or teenagers (younger than eighteen years of age) for collection of information online. Volvo does not solicit or collect customer identifiable information targeted at children and teenagers under eighteen and does not allow anyone else to do so on any Volvo Web Site.

Volvo encourages parents to take an active role in protecting the privacy and security of their children and to prevent the inappropriate use of information about their children. Volvo also supports the development of technologies that help parents to control the collection and use of personal information from children who use online services in their households.

**Cookies and Your Privacy**  
A website may use "cookies" to simulate a continuous connection to that site. This makes it more convenient for users to visit pages within a site without having to reintroduce themselves with each mouse click. Cookies contain only information that users volunteer, and do not have the capability of infiltrating a user's hard drive or taking away personal information. The simple function of a cookie is that of helping the user navigate a website with as little obstruction as possible. Volvo web servers automatically gather general web surfing information about customers' visits within the Volvo Web Site using cookies. Volvo does not use that information except in the aggregate form to determine which sections of our website are generating the most traffic. This helps us to identify how many web site browsers visit each section on our site.

Back to Top

**Cookie Choices in Your Browser**  
Most current browser versions offer users the following options relating to cookies: 

> Accept all cookies.  
>  Accept only cookies that get sent back to the originating server.  
>  Disable cookies.

Another option is for your browser to warn you before accepting a cookie. Every time there is an incoming cookie, a dialog box will ask if you want to accept it. Please consult the user manual or the online Help manual of your browser for instructions on how to customize your browser with your cookie preferences.

**Warranties and Limitations of Liability**  
Information and documents provided on this website are provided "as is" without any warranty. Volvo uses reasonable efforts to include accurate and up-to-date information on this website; it does not, however, make any representations as to its accuracy or completeness. Your use of this website is at your own risk. Volvo, its suppliers, and the other parties involved in creating and delivering the contents of this website are not liable for any damages arising from the use of this site.

**Links to third Party Sites**  
The Volvo website may contain links to third party websites, including websites owned or maintained by authorized Volvo retailers. The linked sites are not under the control of Volvo, and Volvo is not responsible for the contents of any linked site or any link contained in a linked site. Volvo is providing these links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of a link does not imply endorsement of the linked site by Volvo.

**Rights of Use**

**Personal Use of Volvo Web Site Documents**  
Volvo hereby authorizes you to view, copy, download, and print Volvo documents that are available on this website, subject to the following conditions:

The documents may be used solely for personal, noncommercial, and informational purposes. The documents may not be modified. The following copyright notice and permission notice must appear in each document: "Copyright (c) 2000. Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. All rights reserved. Protected by the copyright laws of the United States and international treaties." Copyright, trademark, and other proprietary notices may not be removed.

You may not reproduce, copy, or redistribute the design or layout of the Volvo website, individual elements of the website design, or Volvo logos without the express written permission of Volvo Cars of North America, Inc.

**Commercial Use of Volvo Web Site Materials and Screen Shots**  
Reproduction, copying, or redistribution for commercial purposes of any materials or design elements on the Volvo website is strictly prohibited without the express written permission of Volvo. Permission is granted only when certain criteria are met. To request such permission please send email to customerservice@volvocars.com with the word "Permission" in the subject area, and include the following information in the body of the message:  
The Volvo content you wish to use.  
Where and how will it be used (for example, a book cover, an advertisement, or a brochure).  
Where and how copies will be distributed and to what audience.  
How many copies will be produced and distributed.  
When you intend to publish.  
Other non-Volvo materials that will be associated with the Volvo content.  
Your name, title, company, address, email address, and phone number.

We will evaluate your request as soon as possible. Volvo reserves the right to refuse permission to copy, distribute, broadcast, or publish any of its copyrighted material.

Back to Top

**Licensed Logo Use**  
Use, reproduction, copying, or redistribution of Volvo logos is strictly prohibited without written permission from Volvo. If your organization has a pre-existing agreement with Volvo, that agreement, along with the specific guidelines for each logo, will specify your rights and obligations regarding use of Volvo logos. If you do not have an existing agreement with Volvo, you do not have permission to use Volvo logos. If you have additional questions, please contact Volvo Cars of North America, Inc.

**Downloading Software**  
All software and accompanying documentation made available for download from this website is the copyrighted work of Volvo or its suppliers. The copyright holder retains software and documentation ownership. Ownership is not transferred to you; rather, you are licensed to use the software and documentation.

**Software Rights of Use**  
Software available on the Volvo website is subject to United States export controls. No software from this site may be downloaded or otherwise exported or re-exported (1) into any country to which the United States has embargoed goods; or (2) to anyone on the U.S. Treasury Department's list of Specially Designated Nationals or the U.S. Commerce Department's Table of Denial Orders.

By downloading or using the software, you are agreeing to the foregoing and you are warranting that you are not located in, under the control of, or a national or resident of any such country or on any such list.

**Contact Volvo Customer Service Departments

For Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. related requests:

**  
Customer Service  
Volvo Cars of North America  
7 Volvo Drive  
Rockleigh, NJ 07647  
201-768-7300 or  
1-800-458-1552

**For Volvo Finance North America, Inc. related requests:**  
Customer Service Department  
Volvo Finance North America, Inc.  
Attn: Customer Service Dept.  
1700 Jay Ell Drive  
Richardson, Texas 75081  
1-800-770-8234

**CHANGES**  
We reserve the right to modify or discontinue our Website, Internet services and this Policy at any time. 

Back to Top

VOLVO PRIVACY STATEMENT \- VOLVO DIVERSITY POLICY

**VOLVO CARS OF NORTH AMERICA DIVERSITY POLICY**

Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. is committed to encourage diversity in the work environment and in its retailer network.

**Vision**  
To develop a diverse work force and retailer network where all individuals maximize their potential to achieve business advantage.

**Diversity Policy**  
Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. will take specific actions to achieve diversity, beginning with the visible dimensions: minorities, gender, age, and physical abilities. Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. will align its work force and retailer network with its customers and with changing demographic trends.

**Employee Responsibility**  
It is the responsibility of every employee to uphold this policy, be familiar with Volvo Cars of North America, Inc.'s commitment to fostering diversity, and to ensure compliance with this commitment.

**Harassment Prohibited**  
In keeping with its positive encouragement of diversity, Volvo Cars of North America, Inc. is committed to providing a work place free from hostility; harassment, or intimidation based on a person's race, religion, sex, national origin, age, or disability. Harassment of any kind including, but not limited to, racial slurs, ethnic jokes, and similar conduct, is prohibited.

Employees who feel that they are the victims of employment discrimination or harassing conduct should immediately report the incident to any member of management or to HR Consulting. HR will investigate the incident and determine the necessary action to be taken.

Violation of the harassment section of the diversity policy will result in disciplinary action, up to and including termination.

Back to Top
